Displacement

a representation of a movement from a starting place to an ending
place, with emphasis on the completed movement rather than how it
occurred or the specific starting spot.

Velocity

a description of motion, whose magnitude is the speed and whose
direction “points the way.” The velocity would be the displacement
vector over one time unit, if the motion continued unchanged for the
whole time unit.

Forces

these describe “pushes” by one thing against another. A force is the
cause of acceleration. If you see changes in the motion of something,
it is because there is a force acting on that thing. No such changes
require that the resultant of all forces have zero magnitude.

A representation of a uniform Wind or Current in the air or water.

This example is tied to velocity. It can be interpreted as the
velocity of a dust particle swept up and carried along by an unvarying
wind or current.

Position vector

describes specific location with respect to an origin.

Parametric vector equation for position

Q(t) = P + tV


Decomposition of a vector

Break a vector into 2: multiple of a vector and a vector perpendicular
to the first vector.

When adding vectors, the vectors to add are the ones that are tail to
head then tail to head; the sum of these 2 is the 3rd one which will
have head to head.

Standard position of a vector - the vector has its tail at the origin

magnitude of a vector - |V| = sqrt(v1^2 + v2^2)

V / |V| = (v1 / |V|, v2 / |V|)
magnitude of this vector = 1

therefore, V = |V|(v1 / |V|, v2 / |V|)
		     = |V|(cos theta, sine theta)
p. 11 of Vectors for Trigonometry
------------------------------------------------------------------------
Master Math: Trigonometry

Radian: measure of the central angle subtended by an arc of a circle =
radius of the circle.  ie a central angle subtended by (opposite to)
an arc equal in length to the radius of a circle.

arc length s = r * theta
theta = s/r radians

Trigonometric functions can be defined by
ratios of the sides of a triangle ~ coordinate system using angles in
a standard position ~ arc lengths on a unit circle (circular
functions)

cos s = x
sin s = y
tan s = sin s / cos s = y/x
cot s = cos s / sin s = x/y
sec s = 1 / cos s = 1/x
csc s = 1 / sin s = 1/y


